Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Emory University
- Writings by Seamus Heaney, 1966-2004, Series 8; Boxes 98 – 102; OP2 – OP8
  - Prose, 1966-2004, Subseries 8.2; Box 98 - 102; OP 2-8
    - Holograph notes regarding Wordsworth, Auden, and Eliot, mid 1960s (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Holograph outline for lecture with early teaching materials, ca, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Holograph notes regarding physical imagery [class at Berkley], ca. 1971 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Holograph notes for lecture on Elizabeth Bishop, Oxford, holograph manuscript, 2 December 1992 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Holograph notes for eulogy for Frank Kinahan, February 1993 (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Holograph notes regarding Clare Cavanagh's manuscript on Mandelstam with letter from Princeton University Press, ca. May 1993 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Photocopied pages from notebook relating to trip to Greece, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Holograph notes for introduction to Beowulf, photocopy, 21 March 1995 (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - "Questions and Considerations" regarding the opening of Bellaghy Baun as a center for Heaney poetry, films, and broadcasts, ca. 1996 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - "An Evening with Irish Poets," holograph notes for event at Villanova University, 4 April 2000 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Holograph notes on cards, address at Celebration Dinner 2000, The Irish Literary Society, 13 November 2000 (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - Holograph notes for introduction to lecture at Wolfson College (Oxford), 19 January 2002 (Box 100, Folder 13)
    - Holograph notes for Beowulf reading, undated (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - Holograph notes for Grolier reading, undated (Box 100, Folder 15)
    - Holograph notes for readings on the college circuit, undated (Box 100, Folder 16)
    - Holograph notes for remarks preceding poetry reading celebrating publication of The Field Day Anthology of Irish Literature and achievements of Seamus Deane (Box 100, Folder 17)
    - Holograph notes regarding D.H. Lawrence and Philip Larkin, undated (Box 100, Folder 18)
    - Holograph notes regarding Derek Mahon [for introduction?], undated (Box 100, Folder 19)
    - Holograph note for address regarding influence of personal experience on writing, undated (Box 100, Folder 20)
    - "Odd Coincidences," holograph notes [for reading?], undated (Box 100, Folder 21)
    - Holograph notes on pornography, undated (Box 100, Folder 22)
    - Holograph notes for unidentified after-dinner speech, undated (Box 100, Folder 23)
    - Holograph notes regarding W.H. Auden, undated (Box 100, Folder 24)
    - Holograph notes for unidentified readings, undated (Box 100, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous holograph notes, undated (Box 100, Folder 26)
    - Other prose
    - "Chaucer's Troilus and Crisede," "The Patterns of The Canterbury Tales," graded holograph essays and with notes, ca. 1960s (Box 100, Folder 27)
    - "Wordsworth at Grasmere," carbon typescript with additional notes by Seamus Heaney, early 1970s (Box 100, Folder 28)
    - "My Education with Seamus Heaney," photocopied typescript with many holograph revisions, August 1997 (Box 100, Folder 29)
    - "International Books of the Year," review of Tales from Ovid by Ted Hughes, typescript with holograph corrections, ca. 1997 (Box 100, Folder 30)
    - "Burns's Art Speech," typescript, ca. 1998 (Box 100, Folder 31)
    - "A Note on Michael Warren's Sculptures," typescript with holograph revisions and photocopy of "Simple Measure" by John Hutchinson, ca. 6 November 1998 (Box 100, Folder 32)
    - "Ted Hughes, Birthday Letters, Faber & Faber," review, typescript with holograph revisions, 1999 (Box 100, Folder 33)
    - Introduction of Brendan Kennelly, winner of the Ireland Funds Literary Award, typescript with holograph revisions, 1999 (Box 100, Folder 34)
    - Book jacket blurb for Collected Poems ( I ), by Michael Hartnett, photocopied typescript, ca. 2001 (Box 100, Folder 35)
    - "Not to learn Irish…" statement signed by Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript with revision, undated (Box 100, Folder 36)
    - [Reading introduction?] regarding the work of a poet, holograph, undated (Box 100, Folder 37)
    - Brief history of Field Day Theatre, holograph draft with many revisions, undated (Box 100, Folder 38)
    - Draft review of Greer Hersch's poetry, holograph, undated (Box 100, Folder 39)
    - "A poem is…" [introduction?], typescript with holograph revisions, undated (Box 100, Folder 40)
    - "Atlas of Civilization," review article written for Parnassus, undated (Box 100, Folder 41)
    - "Ghosts: The Fisherman and the Mermaid," typescript, undated (Box 100, Folder 42)
    - "The Impact of Translation," essay, photocopied typescript with holograph corrections, undated (Box 100, Folder 43)
    - Transcription of conversations between Seamus Heaney, David Hammond, Terry Flanagan, and John Reihill regarding life around Lough Erne, undated (Box 100, Folder 44)
    - Untitled essay on reading as a young boy, typescript, undated (Box 100, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified fragments (Box 100, Folder 46)
    - Editing projects
    - Plowshares, volume 10, number 1, special poetry edition edited by Seamus Heaney, Spring 1984, typescripts of articles and poems, related correspondence (Box 100, Folder 47)
    - The School Bag, edited with Ted Hughes, letter from Christopher Reid to Seamus Heaney and Ted Hughes regarding arrangement and current status of the anthology, 5 July 1996 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - The School Bag, letter from Seamus Heaney to Christopher Reid and Ted Hughes regarding sketch for foreword/afterword, 12 July 1996 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 15 July 1996 [1 of 2] (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, 15 July 1996 [2 of 2] (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 16 July 1996 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 18 July 1996 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 22 July 1996 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 25 July 1996 [1 of 2] (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, 25 July 1996 [2 of 2] (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, 26 July 1996 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter and notes from Seamus Heaney 28 July 1996 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 19 August 1996 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 20 August 1996 (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - The School Bag, notes by Christopher Reid on first proofs, Seamus Heaney's holograph notes in response; with letters from Faber & Faber, 22 and 31 October 1996 and holograph notes from Seamus Heaney, 6 November [1996] (Box 101, Folder 14)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letter from Faber & Faber, 18 November 1996 (Box 101, Folder 15)
    - The School Bag, letter from Joanna Mackle to Seamus Heaney regarding promotion of The School Bag, 20 December 1996 (Box 101, Folder 16)
    - The School Bag, proof notes with holograph note from Seamus Heaney to Charley Boyle, 1 January 1997 (Box 101, Folder 17)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, with letters from Seamus Heaney to Matthew Evans, 5 January 1997 and to Joanna Mackle, 5 and 7 January 1997 (Box 101, Folder 18)
    - The School Bag, reading for The Arvon Foundation, "Love and War," poems from The School Bag read by Seamus Heaney, Ted Hughes, Dianna Rigs, Imogene Stubbs, 2 March 1997 (Box 101, Folder 19)
    - The School Bag, drafts of questions and answers by Ted Hughes and Seamus Heaney, with notes from Margaret Hatton and Seamus Heaney, 14 and 18 March 1997 (Box 101, Folder 20)
    - [ The School Bag?], holograph lists of poets and poems, undated (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration with holograph notes in Seamus Heaney's hand, undated, [1 of 6] (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, undated, [2 of 6] (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, undated, [3 of 6] (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, undated, [4 of 6] (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, undated, [5 of 6] (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - The School Bag, photocopied selections under consideration, undated, [6 of 6] (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - The School Bag, foreword, typescript, undated (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - The School Bag, page proofs, pp. 3-199 (Box OP2)
    - The School Bag, page proofs, pp. 3-199 and front matter (Box OP3)
    - The School Bag, page proofs, pp. 200-300 (Box OP4)
    - The School Bag, page proofs, pp. 200-399 (Box OP5)
    - The School Bag, page proofs, pp. 400-599 (Box OP6)
    - The School Bag, page proofs, pp. 400-570 (Box OP7)
    - The School Bag, page proofs, pp. 600-711 (Box OP8)